{"tossups": [{"question": "Note to player: composer and type of work required. Note to moderator: read the score clues in the first and second lines somewhat slowly. In one of these works, low brass play the motif: dotted quarter G-sharp, eighth B-flat, half note A, after which the orchestra plays the half notes C-sharp, D-sharp. Another of these works opens with a faraway cornet playing a slow D-major fanfare, followed by a piccolo playing staccato high Fs accompanied only by snare drum. Abram Stasevich adapted the last of these works into the oratorio Ivan the Terrible. Triple-forte cymbal crashes and tam-tam hits open a rendition of (*) \"Arise, Ye Russian People\" in one of these works which later depicts a \"Battle on the Ice.\" In one of these works, a wife's love for her imaginary husband is depicted via solos for tenor sax and string bass in a famous Romance; that one of these works also contains a sleigh-bell-laden, fourth-movement Troika. For 10 points, name these orchestral works like Alexander Nevsky and Lieutenant Kije.", "answer": "film scores by Sergei Prokofiev [accept anything indicating that the pieces were written to accompany a film or movie and were by Sergei Prokofiev; prompt on cantatas by Prokofiev or orchestral suites by Prokofiev with \"What kind of work were those pieces adapted from?\"]", "subcategory": "Auditory Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "One branch of Oplan Double Barrel, an operation from this country, targeted High Value Targets. During a flag raising ceremony in this country, Antonio Halili was assassinated. Rappler is a news website for this country. A journalist from Russia and Maria Ressa, a journalist from this country, won the 2021 (*) Nobel Peace Prize. This country's leader threatened to jail people who refused the vaccine. Sara, the daughter of this country's president, is running for the mayor of Davao city. The ICC formally authorized a probe into this country's war on drugs. Former boxing champion Manny Pacquio is running to be the president of this country. For 10 points, name this country where Rodrigo Duterte leads from Manila.", "answer": "Philippines", "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events"}, {"question": "Anthony DePalma's book titled for residents of this country discusses the aftermath of an attempt to harvest ten million tons of a major crop here. This country's Ladies in White movement sought to free those imprisoned during the Black Spring, while the song \"Patria y Vida\" has been popularized by recent protests here. Ferries were hijacked by this country's (*) Malecon wall, which names a series of large protests here during the Special Period. After people from this country stormed a Peruvian embassy, the Mariel boatlift occurred. The \"wet foot, dry foot\" policy handling immigrants from this country was in place during a dispute with this country over Eli\u00e1n Gonz\u00e1lez. For 10 points, name this country with a large emigrant population in Miami's \"Little Havana'' neighbourhood.", "answer": "Cuba", "subcategory": "World History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One type of these devices named for Kane partially stores information using NMR. These devices may use CNOT to avoid the no-cloning theorem. Pure states of components of these devices can be visualized on a Bloch sphere. These devices suffer from decoherence when they interact with their environment. These devices can search through a list in O of (*) square root of n time using Grover's algorithm. Applying a type of Fourier transform to the input register can be used to factor arbitrary integers in polynomial time in these devices. These devices can use Shor's algorithm, which could break RSA encryption. For 10 points, name these devices that store information in a superposition of 1s and 0s, qubits.", "answer": "quantum computer [prompt on computer]", "subcategory": "Other Science", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A short story collection in this language called \"The Accusation\" was written by the pseudonymous author Bandi. A judge tries to stop a steelworker and singer from getting a divorce in a novel written in this language called Friend.  In another novel written in this language, a video artist paints flowers on the body of a woman who earlier slit her wrist after being force-fed pork. This language was used to write the Man Asian Literary Prize winner Please Look After Mom. (*) \"Flaming Trees\" is one section of a novel written in this language about the graphic designer Yeong-Hye's struggle with mental illness; that novel is The Vegetarian by Han Kang. For 10 points, name this language in which the works of Kim Jong-Il were initially published.", "answer": "Korean [accept South Korean or North Korean]", "subcategory": "Long Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This philosopher said that \"it's embarrassing to be solemn and treatise-like\" about a phenomenon that includes La Lupe, Bellini's operas, and Tiffany lamps. This philosopher discussed Virginia Woolf's answer to the question \"How in your opinion are we to prevent war?\" in the book Regarding the Pain of Others. This philosopher, who defined the title concept of their most famous essay as (*) \"love of the unnatural: of artifice and exaggeration,\" discussed the work of Diane Arbus in a collection of their New York Review of Books essays, On Photography. This philosopher explored societal beliefs about disease in their books AIDS and its Metaphors and Illness as Metaphor. For 10 points, name this critic and feminist who wrote \"Notes on `Camp'\" and the essay collection Against Interpretation.", "answer": "Susan Sontag [accept Susan Rosenblatt]", "subcategory": "Philosophy", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "If the frequency shifts on isotopic substitution are known, then this quantity can be calculated for isotopic exchange reactions from spectroscopic data. The negative of slope equals this quantity in a Scatchard plot. The natural log of this quantity is plotted against one over T in a plot whose slope is negative delta H over R. This quantity is expressed as a ratio of activities to make it unitless. The (*) Van't Hoff equation relates this quantity to the standard enthalpy change and temperature. Delta G equals negative RT times the natural log of this quantity. The law of mass action states that this quantity equals the ratio of concentrations raised to their stoichiometric coefficients. If the reaction quotient Q is larger than this quantity, then the reverse reaction is favored. For 10 points, name this constant that equals the ratio of the rate of the forward and reverse reactions.", "answer": "equilibrium constant [accept K or Keq]", "subcategory": "Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A book about this activity that discusses the \"unbroken line\" and the \"super-objective\" describes Kostya's lessons with Tortsov. People named for both watching and doing this activity play a major role in the works of Augusto Boal. The biomechanics system of Vsevolod Meyerhold is one approach to performing this action, which was also taught by Sanford Meisner. Uta Hagen and Stella Adler both taught this activity. Lee Strasberg expanded on (*) Konstantin Stainslavski's approach to this activity. Thespis is believed to have pioneered the use of this activity in Ancient Greece. The method form of this activity encourages truly identifying with another's emotions. For 10 points, name this activity often performed on stage in Broadway and Hollywood.", "answer": "acting [accept actor or actress; accept method acting; prompt on theatre or stage or drama or word forms thereof]", "subcategory": "Drama", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A member of this non-Liberian ethnic group named Austin Curtis may have contributed to the development of the Vai script. The Nighthawk Society was founded by members of this ethnic group such as Redbird Smith. The Overhill towns of these people lie near the Tellico River, which names a treaty signed by them. The town of Tahlequah was settled by these people, who also inhabit the (*) Qualla Boundary. A newspaper called the Phoenix was published in these people's language, which uses a syllabary script, by Elias Boudinot. That syllabary used by this ethnic group's language was invented by Sequoyah. For 10 points, name this large tribe that was relocated from North Carolina to Oklahoma on the Trail of Tears.", "answer": "Cherokee [accept Tsalagi or Keetoowah]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One of these objects represents Sojourner Truth with three faces inspired by African masks sharing a single body. Over 1000 of these objects were painted with blue paint in an art exhibit about capital punishment by Julie L. Green. Thirty-nine of these objects painted with motifs that resemble a vulva or a butterfly form part of an installation artwork at the Brooklyn Museum that also includes the names of (*) 999 women on tiles surrounding them. These objects are set atop runners on a triangular table in Judy Chicago's most famous artwork. After John the Baptist was killed on the orders of Salome, his head was often depicted as placed on one of these objects. For 10 points, name these objects featured in The Dinner Party that take up most of the room in individual place settings.", "answer": "plates [accept platters or saucers or chargers; prompt on place settings]", "subcategory": "Other Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "High abundance of one of these general substances can result in the formation of NAQPI. These substances are hydroxylated by enzymes that have a maximum absorption at 450 nanometers when complexed to carbon monoxide, cytochrome P450s. One type of these substances selectively target cyclooxygenase-2. These substances often undergo PEGylation to reduce renal clearance and increase (*) bioavailability. The formation of prostaglandins is limited by one type of these substances called NSAIDs. Most of these substances are metabolized by the liver. The behavior of these substances is studied by pharmacokinetics. For 10 points, name these substances that include paracetamol, which is sold under the brand name Tylenol.", "answer": "drugs [accept medications; accept pharmaceuticals before mentioned; accept anti-inflammatory drugs or NSAIDs or nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drugs; prompt on pills or tablets or medicines; prompt on xenobiotics; anti-prompt on antibiotics; anti-prompt on specific drugs like acetaminophen or paracetamol (you can use Google to check if something is a drug)]", "subcategory": "Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One legend claims that John Scolvus performed this action alongside Didrik Pining and Jo\u00e3o Vaz Corte-Real. This action was supposedly performed by Henry Sinclair, who is sometimes identified with Zichmni, based on drawings in Rosslyn Chapel. One story claims that people who performed this action then met skr\u00e6lings in Helluland and Markland. The Welsh hero (*) Madoc legendarily performed this action, which the crew of the raft Kon-Tiki tried to show could have been performed by Polynesians. Gavin Menzies' book 1421 claimed that Chinese fleets under Zheng He performed this action before it was done by others such as John Cabot. For 10 points, name this action performed by Leif Eriksson and Christopher Columbus, in 1492.", "answer": "sailing to America [accept going to America or discovering America or any description thereof; accept crossing the Atlantic or crossing the Pacific or crossing an ocean; accept any description of a journey to a specific place in the Americas such as the USA, Peru, Canada, Newfoundland, Greenland, Florida, or Alabama]", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "Because of her possession of these objects, a woman is told she has \"bohemian taste'' by her husband, who refers to these objects as \"trash.\" After selling some of these objects, one character goes to the Caf\u00e9 Anglais after leaving his job in the Department of the Interior. Monsieur Lantin sells some of these objects belonging to his wife in a short story titled for them. In a story titled for one of these objects, a man who later becomes a part-time copyist gives his wife the money he had been saving for a (*) hunting trip to go to a Ministry of Education ball. Madame Forestier loans one of these objects to a friend that is in fact worth 500 francs. For 10 points, name this object that the Loisels lost in one of Guy de Maupassant's most famous short stories, where it is revealed to be made of paste.", "answer": "jewels [accept The Necklace or The False Jewels; accept imitation jewelry; accept diamonds or diamond necklace; accept paste jewelry; prompt on paste before read]", "subcategory": "Short Fiction", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Stones named for this ethnic group often contain the symbol of a double disc paired with a Z shape, as well as repeatedly depicting a mysterious namesake \"beast.\" Kingdoms of this ethnic group, which was often led by kings named Drest, included C\u00e9 and Fortriu. Calgacus led a confederation of members of this ethnic group that were defeated by the Romans at the battle of (*) Mons Graupius, as recorded by Tacitus. This no longer extant ethnic group was united with a western neighbour to form the Kingdom of Alba. This ethnic group, whose name may refer to being painted, generally lived north of the Antonine Wall and the Forth and Clyde rivers. For 10 points, name this ethnic group which inhabited Scotland before the Roman conquest.", "answer": "Picts [accept Caledonians or Picti or Albidosi or Cruithni or Prydyn]", "subcategory": "Ancient History", "category": "History"}, {"question": "Part of this country is divided between more pious santri Muslims, named for the students of kyais, and the more syncretic abangan. Many Muslims in this country are part of the Muhammadiyah reformist organization or believe in this country's version of Islam Nusantara. This country contains animists who practice kebatinan, also called kejawen. The three levels of one temple in this country symbolize the realms of (*) feeling or desire, form, and formlessness from bottom to top. Sharia law is observed in Aceh in this country, which also contains the large Buddhist temple Borobudur. For 10 points, name this country with the world's largest Muslim population, many of whom live in Jakarta.", "answer": "Indonesia", "subcategory": "Religion", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "Heine and Lehman studied this phenomenon by asking participants to rank CDs from 1 to 10. This phenomenon was tested by having women undergo a severe or mild \"initiation\" in an experiment conducted by Aronson and Mills. The induced compliance paradigm describes this phenomenon. Subjects were paid either (*) $1 or $20 to turn knobs for an hour in one study of this phenomenon. This phenomenon was studied in a doomsday cult that believed they would be evacuated in a flying saucer. This phenomenon was studied in When Prophecy Fails by Leon Festinger. Rationalization is one way to resolve this phenomenon. For 10 points, name this discomfort that occurs when a person holds two conflicting beliefs.", "answer": "cognitive dissonance", "subcategory": "Social Science", "category": "Social Science"}, {"question": "A version of this object by Andrew Kuo used a yellow part of it to represent repairing systemic racism in a series of designs of these objects also including entries by 2x4 and Na Kim. South Korean students watch one of these objects in a photo next to one of these objects below a ledger with a notebook in a Dread Scott piece. One series of this object painted on a newspaper collage contains a (*) \"White\" example of this object and as well as three stacked examples of this object. These objects are often depicted using encaustic paint in Jasper Johns' most famous paintings. Joe Rosenthal photographed one of these objects being raised above Iwo Jima. For 10 points, name these objects often flown on government buildings in Washington, D.C.", "answer": "American flags [accept Stars and Stripes; prompt on flags]", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Retherford [not Rutherford] accurately predicted one effect in this theory by measuring an energy difference around 1000 megahertz. Infinite integrals in the perturbative approach to this theory led to the first development of renormalization. The abelian gauge group of this theory is U(1). The fine structure constant is this theory's coupling constant. This theory predicts that matter will be created from a strong (*) electric field by the production of electron-positron pairs. Tomonaga, Schwinger and Feynman won the 1965 Nobel Prize in Physics for their work on developing this theory. The force described by this theory is mediated by the exchange of photons. For 10 points, name this theory that describes the electromagnetic force.", "answer": "quantum electrodynamics [or QED; prompt on quantum field theory or QFT; do not accept or prompt on \"quantum chromodynamics\" or \"QCD\"] [the first line refers to the Lamb-Retherford experiment]", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Nell calls this literary character a \"dumb bunny\" while being taught by Miss Bessie before breaking up with Bill in Margaret Atwood's short story collection Moral Disorder. This character is remarked upon in the quote \"Paint must never hope to reproduce the faint half-flush that dies along her throat.\" This character is described as equally pleased by the sunset, a white mule, and \"the bough of (*) cherries some officious fool broke for her.\" This character ranked another character's \"gift of a nine-hundred-years-old name\" with any gift. A painting of this woman by Fra Pandolf depicts her with her common \"spot of joy.\" This character is killed for having a \"heart too soon made glad.\" For 10 points, name this dead title wife of a Robert Browning poem.", "answer": "the Duchess from My Last Duchess [accept the Duchess of Ferrara or My Last Duchess or Lucrezia di Cosimo de' Medici; accept descriptions like the Duke of Ferrara's former wife]", "subcategory": "Poetry", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "In one battle of this non-Roman war, General Bauer surrounded and routed Carl Creutz's cavalry in a Cannae-style battle. Three days after one battle in this war, nearly the entire army of one side surrendered at Perevolochna. During the outset of this war, the Peace of Travendal was signed. The Treaty of Altranst\u00e4dt was signed during this war, which caused Augustus the Strong to abdicate. One side of this war keeps the vessel (*) Gangut to commemorate their victory at a battle of the same name. During this war, one side relieved a siege during a snowstorm at the Battle of Narva. After this war, one side gained Livonia and Ingria as part of the Treaty of Nystad. The Battle of Poltava occurred during this war. For 10 points, name this war where Charles XII of Sweden was defeated by a Russian coalition led by Peter the Great.", "answer": "Great Northern War", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History"}], "bonuses": []}